(DOCTOR WHO THEME)
Doctor Who (1963) 11x01 The Time Warrior (Part 4)
《神秘博士》老版第十一季第一集 《时间勇士》 (第四部分)
【翻译】巴蛮子sz
基于opensubtitles.org 英文字幕翻译
初稿．尚未校对
- You wish for my answer, Doctor?
- I do.
- 你期待我的答案吗，博士？ - 是的
Then here it is.
这就是了
SARAH: No!
不要！
The female, too. It seems I am doubly fortunate.
那个女性也来了，看来我是双重幸运了
- Get up. Get back to work!
- DOCTOR: Linx.
- 起来，回去工作！ - Linx
Can't you see that your prisoners
are physically exhausted?
你看不到你的囚徒身体都已经耗尽了吗？
They've had no sleep and nothing to eat for days.
他们好多天没睡眠没吃东西了
- They can still work!
- Not for much longer.
- 他们还能工作的！ - 不会太长了
LINX: I owe these primitives nothing.
我也不欠这些原始人什么
My only concern is to rejoin our glorious struggle for freedom.
我唯一关心的是重新加入我们争取自由的光荣斗争
DOCTOR: That's such an old tune.
那真是老调重弹
Don't you know there's no such thing
as the super race?
难道你不知道并没有超级种族这样的事吗？
Your Time Lord philosophy is egalitarian twaddle.
你们时间领主的哲学无非是平等主义那些废话
It is a weakness.
这是个弱点
Every species has its own weakness, Linx.
每个物种都有自己的弱点，Linx
For instance, you can only be stunned
by a blow on the probic vent,
举个例子, 只有对准你的通气口猛击，你才会被击晕
that small hole at the back of your neck.
那个通气口在你脖子后面的小洞那里
LINX: In our case, Doctor, it is a strength,
在我们看来，博士，这是种力量
because it means we must always face our enemies.
因为它意味着我们必须永远正面面对我们的敌人
Now, to return to the question of your demise.
现在，回到你的结局这个问题
I think it would be better
我认为最好
if you witnessed first the destruction
of your female companion.
你先目睹一下你女性同伴的灭亡
Well done, Rubeish.
干得好，Rubeish
- Doctor, are you all right?
- Yes.
- 博士，你还好吗？  - 是的
Yes. The blast was too brief.
还好，刚才的冲击波还太弱
But I wouldn't have been in a few moments.
但我也得缓一下才行
- Thank you very much, Sarah.
- Oh, pleasure.
- 非常谢谢你，莎拉  - 哦，乐意帮忙
Hadn't I better be getting on with the rest of your plan?
我是不是应该继续你的计划？
- Yes. All right, but be careful.
- You, too, Doctor.
- 是的，继续吧，不过要小心  - 你也是，博士
Right. Well, if we can secure our friend here,
好。嗯，如果我们能限制住这位朋友
we can get on with the job of restoring
his wretched victims.
我们还可以继续恢复这些可怜的受害者
Will this help?
这能帮上忙吗？
Rubeish, you're invaluable, my dear chap.
Rubeish, 你真是个无价之宝，亲爱的伙计
- Bloodaxe.
- Captain.
- Bloodaxe  - 头儿？
Fetch me Linx.
把 Linx 给我叫来
Fetch me that scabby-faced stoat from his burrow.
把那个面无表情的家伙从他的洞穴里弄出来
At once, Captain.
马上，头儿
Well, that should hold him for a while,
even on this planet.
好了，这样应该能困住他一阵了，即使是在这个星球上？
Why this planet?
为什么说“这个星球”？
Well, in his own environment, he weighs several tons.
哦，在他们的环境下，他重达好几吨
Fortunately, his muscles have been designed
for load bearing rather than leverage
幸运的是, 他的肌肉是为承重而设计的, 而不是力量(?)
Fascinating.
有意思
I'd always assumed that creatures
from a high-density planet
我一直以为来自高密度星球的生物
would have developed a pressure-balanced physiology.
会演化出压力平衡的生理机能
For example, if you take certain types of seaweed...
比如，如果你找几样海藻...
BLOODAXE: Linx! Linx!
-Linx?
-DOCTOR: Who speaks?
- Linx  - 谁在说话
Captain Irongron commands your presence.
Irongron 队长命令你过去
Tell him I'm busy.
告诉他我正忙
Well, come soon or we come and fetch you.
好吧, 快来, 否则我们来拎你
Who is Irongron? Is he a nice chap?
Irongron 是谁？ 是个好人吗？
Well, I wouldn't recommend him
for the Royal Society.
反正，我不会推荐他加入皇家学会
All right, Rubeish, you know how
to bring these people round?
好了，Rubeish，你知道怎么把这些人唤醒过来了吧
- Yes. A simple, repetitive optical...
- Yes, quite so.
- 是，很简单，一直进行光学的...
- 对，就这样
- I'll leave you to get on with it.
- What do you propose to do?
- 我就把这个事情留给你了
- 你打算干什么去？
I was going to preset this osmic projector.
我原本正要去调整好锇投射器
Send these people back to their own time.
好把这些人送回原来的时代
But now I have to find a way of stalling Irongron.
但现在我必须得找到一个方法拖住 Irongron
The robot! Yes, of course.
那个机器人！对了，当然
That ought to give him something to think about.
那应该可以让他费点脑筋了
Thief!
小偷！
You common scullion, stand aside!
你，粗鄙的下人，站一边去！
How dare you obstruct me?
I shall have you flogged.
胆敢妨碍我？我会让人抽你的
Oh, so, a lady, are you?
哦，这么说，你是位小姐？
- A lady dressed as a serving wench?
- I'm hungry.
- 一位小姐穿得跟个侍女一样？
- 我饿了
Please let me go. I've tasted neither
bread nor meat for nearly a month.
请放我走吧，我已经快一个月没有吃过面包或白面了
No, nor done no work for longer
by the look of you.
看样子你也是很久没有劳动了
All right, my girl, I'll give you bread and cheese,
好吧，姑娘，我会给你面包和奶酪的
but you'll have to earn it.
但你要用劳动来换
Who are you?
你是谁
DOCTOR: I am a gift to Captain Irongron
我是送给 Irongron 队长的礼物
from the one who made me, my master, Commander Linx.
来自我的主人，指挥官Linx，是他创造了我
It is indeed the robot, Bloodaxe, though somewhat different in shape.
还真是那个机器人，Bloodaxe，虽然形状上有点不同
And I remember, Linx promised
to make me a second iron man,
而且我记得，Linx 承诺过给我再造一个机器人的
one that would obey my voice.
一个会服从我的语音命令的
But why has Linx sent you?
不过为什么 Linx 送你来？
Why has he not himself obeyed my summons?
为什么他自己不服从我的召见？
My master toils in his workshop to make you more fighting robots.
我的主人正在他的工作间里忙碌，给你造更多的战斗机器人
- He sent me as proof of his goodwill.
- What?
- 他派我来以证明他的善意   - 什么？
- Now I must return.
- Hold.
- 现在我必须回去了  - 停下
I would see something of the mettle of this gift.
我要看看这份礼物的品质如何
- Can you fight, iron man?
- That is my purpose.
- 你能战斗吗，铁人？  - 那是我存在的目的
Then fight me.
那来跟我打
I was programmed to fight for you,
not against you.
我被设计成为你战斗，而不是与你战斗
- Cease thy gabble and fight.
- You will damage my circuits.
- 少废话，开打！  - 你会毁坏我的电路的
Fight, iron man,
战斗吧，铁人
or you'll return to Linx in as
many pieces as did your brother.
要不就把你砍碎了送回 Linx 那里去，跟你兄弟一样
Hold.
停下
It's truly a marvel, Captain.
Never have I seen a finer swordsman.
这真很神啊，头儿，从来没见过比这更好的剑士
Ah, 'tis great sport this, Bloodaxe.
Draw your sword and join me.
啊，这是很好的锻炼啊，Bloodaxe，拿出剑来加入我吧
We'll try this creature's strength to the utmost.
我们来测试一下这个家伙的极限
Get on!
开始吧！
(SWORDS CLASHING)
What's that?
那是什么？
Oh, fighting again in the great hall, I'll warrant.
噢，又在大厅里打斗了，我敢肯定
Men were ever like children, fond of noise and brawling.
男人们就跟小鸡一样，就喜欢吵闹和打斗
Get about your work, girl.
操心你的活儿吧，姑娘
Hold!
停下！
Hold, I say!
停下，我说了！
We must slow this iron man's speed a little.
我们得让这个铁人的速度慢一点
Stick me some crossbow bolts in the creature.
用十字弓给这个家伙钉几下
We'll see if it fights as well with
a crossbow bolt or two in its gizzard.
我们倒要看看，肚子上中了一两箭之后它是不是还这么能打
And if that fails,
如果不行，
we'll lop off its head and try again then.
我们砍掉它的头再试
(MEN LAUGHING)
Isn't that a bit unsporting, old man?
那么做是不是有点不光明正大啊，老家伙
I mean, sitting ducks and all that.
我是说，打鸭子这样的搞法
This iron man talks like some Norman ninny.
这个铁人说话有点像某个诺曼底傻瓜
- Lift up your visor.
- I cannot reveal my face, Irongron.
- 抬起你的面具
- 我不能揭示我的面目，Irongron
Why?
为什么？
Because if I did, it might give you a seizure.
如果我那样做的话，你可能会被吓晕
- The wizard!
- Well, I did warn you, didn't I?
- 那个巫师！  - 怎样，我的确警告过你，对吧？
Seize him!
抓住他！
No.
不
The sword is too quick and clean a death for you.
这种死法对你来说太快太干净了
Well, since you are a wizard,
这样，既然你是一位巫师
then by wizardry shall you die.
你应该死于巫术之下
Not so much of that oatmeal, girl.
It's only pikemen we're feeding, not horses.
不要放那么多燕麦，姑娘，我们喂的是枪兵，不是马
Hey, watch that pot.
嘿，看着那个罐子
If you burn Lord Irongron's stew,
he'll have your liver cut out.
如果你烧糊了 Irongron 的食物，他会把你的肝都挖出来的
- Is all this for Irongron?
- Him and his chamber guard.
- 这些都是给  Irongron 的么？  - 他和他的贴身侍卫
- How many's that?
- Half a dozen.
- 多少人？  - 半打吧
- You're full of questions, girl.
- Don't the guards on the gate get stew?
- 你问题还真多，姑娘  - 门口的守卫不吃饭吗？
What? Meat for those common creatures?
I should say not.
什么？给那些杂役做饭？要我说不用
They'll have oatmeal, the same as the rest of us,
他们吃燕麦粥，跟我们一样
and lusty enough they are on that.
他们有这个就不错了
So you watch yourself if ever you take out that skillet.
所以你拿出那个平底锅的时候小心一点
I'm not afraid of men. They don't own the world.
我不怕男人，世界又不都是他们的
Why should women always
have to cook and carry for them?
为什么应该是女人给他们做饭、整理东西？
- What else should we do?
- Stand up for ourselves.
- 我们还能做什么？  - 为我们自己站起来
Tell the men you're tired of working for them like slaves.
告诉男人你已经厌倦了像个奴隶一样为他们干活
- We are slaves.
- Then you should set yourselves free.
- 我们就是奴隶  - 那你们就应该解放自己
- Oh, and how should we do that?
- Don't you want to be free?
- 噢，我们怎么能那么干？  - 你不想要自由吗？
Women will never be free while there are men in the world, girl.
女人永远不会有自由，只要这世界还有男人，姑娘
- We have our place.
- What subservient poppycock.
- 我们有自己的位置 - 哪来的歪理邪说
- You're still living in the Middle Ages.
- Eh?
- 你们还生活在中世纪  - 嗯？
- Nothing.
- You're young and foolish, girl.
- 没啥  - 你还年轻，幼稚，姑娘
And I warn you, keep those thoughts to yourself
而且我警告你啊，收起你那些想法
or you'll not live long enough to grow wiser.
否则你都活不到变聪明点那一天
I must tell them their food will soon be ready.
我得去告诉他们，食物很快就会准备好了
Look at that great spider!
看那里有个大蜘蛛！
(SCREAMS)
♪ Oh, see me dance the polka. Oh, see me... ♪
哦，看我跳段波尔卡舞，哦，看我...
(RUBEISH HUMMING)
Ah, that's it.
啊，行了
Come on. Stand up, my dear chap. Come on.
加油啊，站起来，亲爱的朋友，来啊
Come on. That's it. Now listen, all of you.
来吧，对了。现在听着，你们所有人
You've been kidnapped, but you're about to be rescued, I hope.
你们被绑架了，现在要解救你们，我期望是
There's a machine here that'll send you home again.
这里有台机器是送你们回家的
Unfortunately, I don't know how to work it,
不幸的是，我不知道怎么操作它
and the chap who does has vanished.
而知道的人又消失了
But I expect he'll pop up again.
He usually does.
但我期待着他又冒出来，他经常这样
But the important thing is,
但重要的事情是
until then, you must carry on working
as if you were still hypnotised.
在那之前，你们要继续工作，假装你们还是在催眠状态下
- Can I ask...
- Morrison, don't start asking a lot of awkward questions
- 我能问问...  - Morrison, 先别问那些让我难堪的问题
I assure you, I don't know the answers any more than you do.
我先向你保证，对于答案，我知道得并不比例多
-IRONGRON: Linx!
Back to work, everyone. Someone's coming.
回去工作吧，所有人。有人来了
Linx, you dog!
Linx，你这条狗！
Where are you hiding?
你躲在哪儿？
Oh, there you are, you dragon-eyed toad.
喔，你在这里啊，你个大眼睛的蟾蜍
- Who put these bonds on you?
- The Doctor.
- 谁把你绑起来了  - 博士
I was struck from behind.
我被从后面袭击了
- Where is he?
- The Doctor is dying.
- 他在哪儿?  - 博士要没命了
What method have you chosen to destroy him?
你选择什么方法灭掉他？
Thank you, sir, for your charm and old world courtesy.
谢谢你, 先生，因为你的魅力和传统的礼貌
May I ask the purpose of this tomfoolery?
我能问问这些无聊的举动都是在干什么吗?
If you're going to have me shot,
why don't you get on with it?
如果你打算射杀我，为什么不直接来呢？
I would not have your death be in vain, good sorcerer.
我不会让你白死的, 我的好术士
I intend that it shall be of some use to me.
我觉得这我来说应该还有些用处
Nothing that I do will be of use to you, Irongron.
我做的任何事情对你都没有用处, Irongron
Oh, nay, Doctor, but you're wrong.
哦, 不, 博士, 你错了
These knaves of mine lack practice with their star weapons.
我的这帮喽罗对于这些星星武器还缺乏练习
A living target will give them a chance
一个活动的靶子, 是他们的好机会
to better their aim before tomorrow's battle.
可以在明天的战斗之前提高一点瞄准能力
You, shoot!
你, 开枪！
(IRONGRON LAUGHING)
These knaves of mine aim so ill, Doctor,
我这些喽罗瞄准能力是如此的烂, 博士
that you are mayhap safer to stand still.
也许你站着不动还安全一点
You, shoot!
你, 开枪！
The aim improves, Doctor. Be patient.
这次有进步, 博士．耐心点
We shall hit the target all in good time.
我们会在某个好时候击中目标的
I'm in no great hurry, I assure you.
我一点也不着急, 我向你担保
Oh, beshrew me, but I grow fond of this fellow.
哦, 该死, 不过我开始喜欢这个家伙了
Shoot when you please, lads, and a bag of gold
to the one that brings him down.
你们随意射击吧, 小伙子们, 把他射倒的人可以得到一袋金子
(GUNS FIRING)
That noise. I can hear shooting!
那个声音．我能听到有枪声！
- More tomfoolery.
- What is it? What's happening?
- 更多的胡闹  - 是什么, 怎么回事？
They captured Sir Edward's sorcerer,
this fellow, the Doctor,
他们抓住了爱德华爵士的术士, 那个叫博士的家伙
and now they're slaying him in the great hall
现在他们正在大厅里杀他呢
with these devil's weapons of theirs.
用的是那些魔鬼的武器
For the life of me, I can't see what's wrong
with a good, old-fashioned broadsword.
我这一辈子, 都看不出使用旧式腰刀有什么不好
By the stars! This fellow hops around
like a flea on a griddle.
星星在上！这家伙跳来跳去, 跟个跳蚤似的
Give me a weapon. I will destroy him.
给我一把武器, 我来消灭他
What? Would you spoil good sport, old toad?
什么? 要破坏我们的娱乐活动吗, 老蟾蜍？
(GUNS FIRING)
Doctor!
博士
Well done, Sarah.
做得好, 莎拉
Just like a daring young man
on the flying trapeze. Come on.
像个勇敢的年轻人在空中飞人, 快来
(BANGING ON DOOR)
(IRONGRON SHOUTING)
Sarah, wait.
莎拉, 等等
Come on.
快来
(DOCTOR WHISTLING)
Do you know, I think that was one of
the most active days that I've had in years.
你知道吗, 我觉得这是我在这几年之内运动最多的几天
Well, it's not as if I was a lad any more,
好吧, 我并不是一个小伙子了
once you're over 200.
尤其你已经过了 200 岁之后
So then, Doctor, your plans have miscarried, I fear.
看来, 博士, 你的计划被打乱了, 恐怕
- What will you do now?
- Oh, wait a bit.
- 你现在怎么办？  - 哦, 等一小会儿
Give the potion time to work and then go back.
给点时间让药水生效, 然后回去
- Doctor, you can't!
- Sarah, I must.
- 博士, 你不能！  - 莎拉, 我必须
Rubeish and all those scientists are there.
Rubeish 和那些科学家都还在那儿
Linx's spaceship is just about ready for takeoff,
Linx 的飞船也马上就要可以起飞了
and when that happens, there'll be a tremendous explosion.
到那个时候, 那里将有一场非常强烈的爆炸
All that will be left of that castle
will be a pile of stones.
那座城堡能剩下来的就只是一堆乱石
- But, Doctor, how can the castle go?
- Just believe me, sir.
- 但是, 博士, 城堡怎么能消失呢？  - 尽管相信我吧, 爵士
When Linx goes, it goes.
如果 Linx 走了, 它也就没了
Irongron's castle is to be destroyed
by sorcery? Then all is well.
Irongron 的城堡会被毁于魔法？那就万事大吉了
There are innocent people in that castle, my lady,
那座城堡里面还有无辜的人, 夫人
and I don't like the idea of anybody going up in smoke.
而且我也不喜欢让任何人烟消云散
Not even Irongron.
即使是 Irongron
If you're going back, then I'm coming with you.
如果你打算回去, 那我跟你一起
I, too, will come with you if my master permits.
我也跟你去, 如果我的主人允许的话
Well, thank you. Thank you both.
好, 谢谢你, 谢谢你们俩
I can do with all the help I can get.
我可以用我能得到的一切帮助来做
Thank you, my friends. Your work is finished.
谢谢你, 我的朋友们, 你们的工作结束了
You may rest now for a time
until the power build-up is complete.
你们可以休息一会儿, 等能量聚集过程完成
Doctor, I think you'd better get a move on.
博士, 我觉得你最好赶紧行动
I've a feeling time's beginning to run out.
我有一种感觉, 时间快不够了
- Good evening.
- It's working, Doctor. Look.
- 晚上好  - 起作用了, 博士, 看
Aye, the villains sleep like innocent babes.
啊, 这些恶棍像无知的婴儿一样睡着了
Good.
很好
Well, we'll wait a bit to be on the safe side, then we'll go in.
好, 我们先在安全的地方等一会儿, 然后进去
At last, Doctor, there you are.
终于, 博士, 你来啦
Something most interesting happening here.
最有意思的一件事发生了
Yes, I see. Where's Linx?
是的, 我看到了．Linx 哪儿去了？
I don't know. He started his spaceship going then cleared off.
我不知道, 他启动了他的飞船就不见了
Where's the osmic projector?
It was over there on the table.
锇金属投射器在哪儿？之前是在那个桌子上的
He put everything back inside the ship.
他把所有东西放回飞船里面了
I'll just have to take it out again, won't I?
看来我必须得再去把它拿出来, 是吧？
Hal, scout around the castle.
Hal, 在城堡里四处巡查一下
See if Irongron and his men are sleeping.
看 Irongron 和他的人是不是在睡觉
If they are, disarm them and come back here.
如果是, 偷走他们的武器然后回来
What are you going to do, Doctor?
你打算怎么做, 博士？
Get the osmic projector.
Fortunately, it's an independent unit.
拿到锇金属投射器．幸运的是, 它是个独立器件
- Can't you switch this thing off?
- Well, I can try.
- 你能关掉这个吗？  - 嗯, 我可以试试
Suppose you don't succeed?
假如你不成功呢？
Then we've got between five and ten
minutes to get out of here
那我们就只有５到１０分钟的时候离开这里
before we're all blown to kingdom come.
否则就会被炸回老家了
(MAN SNORING)
- Couldn't you shut it down?
- No, the drive system is sealed.
- 你就不能关掉它吗？  - 不, 驱动系统被封住了
Linx must have taken the activator key.
I managed to get a hold of this, though.
Linx 肯定拿走了激活钥匙．不过, 我设法拿到了这个
I was lucky to get it out with the drive running.
很幸运, 引擎还在运行的时候我把它拿出来了
I think that should do it.
我觉得这个可行
I've got to send them back one at a time.
我可以每次送一个人回去
Get the first one to stand over there,
will you, Rubeish?
把第一个人拉到那里站着．行吗, Rubeish？
Come on, Morrison.
来吧, Morrison
All right, Rubeish, come over here.
I may want you to take over.
好了, Rubeish, 到这里来, 我想让你接手
Now then, all you have to do is this,
现在, 你只需要做这个
- this and this. Get it?
- Yeah.
- 再这个和这个, 明白了吗？   - 是
Right, here goes.
好, 走你
Right, that ought to surprise them
back at the research centre.
好了, 这应该会让研究中心的人大吃一惊了
- Next gentleman, please.
- Come on.
- 下一位绅士, 请过来  - 来吧
(ALL LAUGHING)
For the last time, Linx,
let there be no more talk of leaving.
最后一次跟你说, Linx, 不要再说什么离开的话了
And I tell you for the last time,
I am leaving now.
我也要最后一次跟你说, 我要走了
Our alliance is at an end.
我们的联盟到头了
It ends when I say it ends and not before.
我说到头了才能到头, 早了不行
You would be well advised to march
from this castle now and capture another.
强烈建议你们现在就从这个城堡出发, 另外再夺取一座
Soon you will have need of it.
很快你们就对它有需求了
- He threatens us, Captain.
- He does not understand our ways.
- 他在威胁我们, 头儿  - 他不懂我们的路子
Tomorrow, Linx, we smite the enemy, hip and thigh!
明天, Linx, 我们击杀敌人
But tonight, we feast.
但今晚, 我们先享乐一番
By your dawn, I shall be 700 million miles from here.
在你们黎明的时候, 我已经在7亿公里之外了
Can I be concerned with the fate of primitives?
我还会在意原始人的命运吗？
(ALL LAUGHING)
What did he mean, Captain?
他什么意思, 头儿？
He is a toad.
他是个蟾蜍
Who knows what a toad thinks?
谁知道一只蟾蜍在想什么？
Aye, Captain, 'tis truly said.
啊, 头儿, 这真是大实话
This stew has made me heavy.
这食物让我觉得头晕
Eh?
嗯?
That's Linx.
那是 Linx
Send the rest of them back.
I'll try and keep him busy.
把其他人送回去．我会尽量让他腾不出手来
(SNORING)
Trickery! Sorcery!
骗术！巫术！
What sorcery! Treachery.
什么骗术！巫术！
That toad Linx bewitched us all!
那只蟾蜍对我们所有人施了魔法
- Now you, Professor.
- I really don't think
- 到你了, 教授  - 我还真不觉得
- I ought to go and leave you.
- Off you go now.
- 我应该先走, 把你留在这里  - 你感觉走吧
- Now then, this, this and this.
- Well, goodbye and good luck.
- 现在, 这个, 这个和这个  - 好, 再见, 祝你好运
It really was the most fascinating experience.
还真是最有意思的体验
I hope you and the Doctor will be all right.
See you back at research centre.
我期望你和博士都没事．在研究中心见
SARAH: Doctor!
博士
So...
这么说...
destroy my castle by sorcery, would you, toad face?
用魔法毁灭我的城堡, 你会吗, 蟾蜍脸？
Well, Irongron's magic is too strong for you!
好, Irongron 的魔法对你来说太强了！
Now listen, dog!
现在听着, 小狗！
In minutes now, this castle
will be destroyed by the sorcery.
几分钟之后, 这个城堡将会被魔法摧毁
If you'd save your miserable skins, then get you gone!
如果你还想挽救你们可悲的皮囊, 赶紧跑吧
Flee, dogs!
逃啊, 小狗们！
Flee for your life! Come on, waken, you dogs!
逃命去吧！快, 醒醒, 狗崽子们
And flee! Flee for your lives, you dogs!
逃吧, 逃命去吧, 狗崽子们
Waken! Waken up! Now flee!
醒醒！起来！赶紧逃吧
Doctor, do get up. We've got to get you out.
博士, 赶紧起来啊, 我们得把你弄出去
(HIGH-PITCHED BUZZING)
Something's gone wrong.
有事情不对了
He must have hit the takeoff button too soon.
他肯定提前按了起飞按钮
Come on, we've got about a minute
to get out of here. Quick! Run!
快点, 我们只有一分钟的时间跑出去．快, 跑！
(HIGH-PITCHED BUZZING BUILDS)
(BUZZING INTENSIFIES)
Well, you can tell Sir Edward
that his problems are over, Hal.
好了, 你可以告诉爱德华爵士, 他的问题都没有了, Hal
Irongron, his castle,
Irongron, 和他的城堡
his magic weapons and his sorcerer,
they're all destroyed.
他的魔法武器和他的术士, 他们都毁灭了
Will you not tell him yourself, Doctor?
你不亲自去告诉他吗, 博士？
He will reward you well. We owe you much.
他会重重奖赏你的, 我们欠你很多
I'm sorry. I'm afraid we must be off.
我很抱歉, 恐怕我们得走了
- Goodbye, Hal.
- Goodbye, Doctor.
- 再见, Hal  - 再见, 博士
- Goodbye.
- 再见   - 再见
You are truly a great magician, Doctor.
你真是一个伟大的魔法师, 博士
To tell you the truth, Hal, I'm not a magician at all.
跟你说实话, Hal, 我完全不是个魔法师
I'm not so sure about that.
我可不太确定
(WHOOSHING)